Guide to the Robert Herrick Papers 1887-1960
University of Chicago Library
- Series III: Literary Manuscripts
  - Subseries 3: Short Fiction
    - Short Fiction, "If One Cares," Feb. 1925, typescript "The Storm" [1925?] typescript (Cf. The End of Desire.) "Notes by the Way," Jan. 22, 1925, typescript (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - "A Plot of Fair Women," March 14, 1925, typescript (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Stories and Sketches [late 20's?] typescripts, "Boom-Bust" (See also Box 14, Folder 5.) "The Great Game" "Machine Medicine" "Midnight Conversations" (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - "Stations of the Cross" (Wanderings, 1925), typescript, early version (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - "Stations of the Cross," typescript, 1 p. notes, fragments and text, early version (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - "Stations of the Cross," typescript, closer to final version, folded sheet at end: holograph notes on "Stations of the Cross" and "Magic" (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - "The Adventures of Ti Chat," April 6, 1924 (Wanderings), typescript, early version (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - "The Adventures of Ti Chatte," typescript, early version and fragments (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - "The Adventures of Ti Chatte," typescript, close to published version, end missing (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - "The Further Adventures of Ti Chatte," 1925, typescript, not part of Wanderings-an animal version (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - "Magic," March 19, 1924 and June 1924 (Wanderings), typescript, 2 early versions (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - "Magic," typescript, early version (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - "Magic," typescript, early version (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - "The Passions of Trotsky," July 1924 (Wanderings), typescript (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Wanderings, 1925, typescript, complete final version: "Magic,", "Stations of the Cross" (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Wanderings, complete, final version: "The Adventures of Ti Chatte" (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Wanderings, complete, final version: "The Passions of Trotsky" (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - "Mickey Grows Up," Aug. 1931, typescript and 1 p. holograph notes (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 4: Plays
    - "The Crime" [about 1910?] typescript, scenario (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - "The Lady in the Glass," holograph, in 3 notebooks (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - "The Lady in the Glass," typescript (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - "The Flaw," holograph (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - "Making Good," March 14, 1913, holograph, black notebook (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - "The Second Fall of Man," Feb. 1913, holograph, black notebook; scenario, typescript (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - "The Second Fall of Man," 1913, typescript (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 5: Travelogues
    - "Silhouettes from Egypt," 1926, typescript. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Writings on Egypt, "Silhouettes from Egypt," title page only "Sight Seeing in Egypt." "Silhouettes in Egypt," 1926, typescript, another version (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Travelogues, "An Eighteenth Century Journey," March 1928, typescript, several versions, about Mallorca, Spain, Italy "The Return," typescript, incomplete (material here moves in the direction of a short story. Note reference to Ti Chatte.) "The Trip," typescript (incomplete short story?) (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Mexico and Florida, "Capingo, Mexico, April 3, 1933," typescript "Mexico Then and Now, 1887-1933," typescript "About Florida" [1934?] typescript "The Land of Lathe and Plaster" [1934?] typescript "The Sunshine State" [1934?] typescript "The Sunshine State," Nov. 1934, typescript, another version (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 6: European and Literary Notebooks
    - European Notebooks (2) 1892, 1895 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - European and Literary Notebooks (3), European and Literary Notebook 1895 (contains The Web of Life) Literary 1890 To Luigi Cerot [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Literary Notebooks (2), The Real World 1900 1898-1906 Loose pp., [1902?] (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Literary Notebooks (3), July 1904 December 1906 "The Doctors Office" (See also Notebook December 1906, above.) (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Literary Notebooks (4), Notes on New Work November 1910 Titled "The Healer, begun York, Me., August 1910" but book contains notes for One Woman's Life, September 1, 1911 "A Song in the Heart," May 4, 1913, notes Revision of Great Adventure, May 18, 1913 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Literary Notebooks (3), From Great Adventure [1913] One Woman's Life and "The Gas House" "War" [1915?] (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Literary Notebooks (2), Notes Paris, Nov., Dec. 1916, contains loose sheets dated Feb. 1917 "The Heart of Man" [1919?] (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Series IV: Essays and Lectures
  - "To the Editor of the Nation," Nov. 30, 1891, holograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - "The University of Chicago," 1895, in notebook titled English Comp. 1893, published Scribner's, 18 (Oct. 1895), 399-417 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - "Philip Stanley Abbot," Nov. 5, 1896, typescript (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - No title: about the theatre [early 20th century] holograph (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Editorials [1906] holograph, written for anonymous publication in Saturday Evening Post or The World's Work, "The Beam in the Eye" (newspaper gossip) "Fifty Million Dollars for a University" (University of Chicago) "Football and the Sporting Fraternity" "A Great American Institution" (Marshall Field, department store) "The Great American Play Ground" "An Honest Fortune" (Marshall Field) "A New Remedy for Talk" (injunction against strikers' talking) "The Power of Property" (city planning) "Some Parlor Socialists" (Ibsen and Carl Schurz) "The Square Deal and the Tariff" "Tom Lawson and Daniel Defoe" "Too Many Universities" "Wanted a Male Poet" "The Ways of Smart People" (The House of Mirth, Edith Wharton) "What a Rich Man Owes to His Country" (Marshall Field) "The Good of Examinations" "Does Experience Teach?" "Friends of the Republic" "How Much Money Should a Man Have?" "Heart Interest and Other Interest" "The Man not the Measure" "A Toss Up" "The Writing on the Wall" "More Irrigation" "Zola in the Stockyards" "A Conservative Physician" "The Big Stick and China" "Wanted Celebrities" "Vested Right and Other Rights" "A Case of Belated Conscience" (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - "Thackeray," July 18, 1911, typescript and holograph, notes, text and fragments (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - "The American Background," March 7, 1912, notebook, typescript, published as "The Background of the American Novel," Yale Review, 3 (Jan. 1914), 213-233 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - "The American Novel," 1914, typescript, published Yale Review, 3 (April 1914), 419-437 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - "The Far Wide Spaces," 1915, fragment, review of Ernest Poole, The Harbor (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - "American Pacifism" [1917?] typescript (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - "Hoover," 1920, typescript, 2 versions, published as "For Hoover," Nation 110 (June 5, 1920), 750-751 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - "New England and the Novel," 1920, typescript and printed version, published Nation, 111 (Sept. 18, 1920), 323-325 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - "Telling the truth in Fiction," May 3, 1922, typescript, several versions, incomplete (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - "The Drift of Opinion," 6 lectures delivered Autumn and Winter, 1922-23, typescript (See "The Drift of Opinion," below.), Printed advertisement "Political Opinion" "Economic Opinion" "Social Opinion" (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - "The Drift of Opinion," 1922-23, "The Realistic Picture" "The Romantic Picture" "The Idealistic Solution" (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - "Workshop of the Modern Novelist," 1922-23, typescript (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - "New Bottles" [1922-23?] typescript, No title: [New Technique of Character Portrayal, Epic vs. Individual, n.d.] related to "New Bottles"? (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - "Has the World Changed?" [1923?] typescript (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - "A Visit to Henry James," Jan. 15, 1923, typescript, variations, published Yale Review 12 (July, 1923), 724-741 and in The Manly Anniversary Studies in Language and Literature, Chicago, 1923, pp. 229-242 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - "Mr. Master's Prose" [1924?] typescript, fragment (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - "Some Novels from Europe" [1925] typescript, 2 versions and fragments, published as "Some European Novels in Translation," Yale Review, 14 (Jan. 1925), 366-373 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - "Human Nature as It Is-or Isn't," Sept. 23, 1930, typescript (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - "Our Super-Babbitt, a Recantation," 1930, printed copy of Nation 131 (July 16, 1930), 60-62 (See also "Hoover," above.) (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - "The Colonial" [1931] typescript, notes, fragments, published as "Henry James," American Writers on American Literature, John Macy, ed., New York: Horace Live-right, Inc., 1931 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - "America the False Messiah" [1931] typescript, criticism by R. M. Lovett, published in Behold America, S. D. Schmalhausen, ed., New York: Farrar & Rinehart, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - "Age Replies" [1933?] typescript; "I Don't Believe in Democracy," 1933, typescript, published Nation 137 (July 26, 1933), 103-104 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - "Mark Twain and the American Tradition," Nov. 1, 1935, typescript, text and earlier version, associated clipping, published Mark Twain Quarterly, 2 (Winter 1937), 8-11 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - "Symposium on Americanism," 1936, typescripts and printed version, published as "The American Way," Partisan Review and Anvil, 3 (April 1936), 7-8 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Reviews and Essays: Cultural, typescripts, "Radio-O-Oh!" [1927?] "The Booze Age," 1931, published New Republic, 68 (Oct. 7, 1931), 213-214 "Sacredness of Contract," November 22, 1931 "Forty Years in the Wilderness" [1932?] 2 versions Frank Bigelow Tarbell materials, 1934, for Dictionary of American Biography Article (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Essays: Politics and Civilization, typescripts, "Friends of General Wood" [1920?] "Passion, Love, Marriage-All or One?" [1923?] and "Notes on Love," May 7, 1923 (Items seem related.) "The English Way with the Race Problem" [1924] and "The French Way" [1924] published as "The Race Problem in the Caribbean," Nation, 118 (June 11, 1924), 675-676 and (June 18, 1924), 699-700 "Why I Shall Vote for La Follette" [1924?] "Being Dictated To" [1928?] "The Way We Do Down East," Sept. 20, 1930 "Hard Times-A Challenge to Women" [1930?] 3 versions "Let Us Talk about Unpleasant Things," 1932, 3 versions, published Harper's, 165 (Oct. 1932), 598-604 "Birth Pains" [1932?] "A Dictator is Grand!" May 22, 1933 "Politics" [New Deal] (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Editorials, typescripts, "A Dangerous Topic" [1916?] "The Quality of Imagination in American Life" [1918?] "New Ideals for Women" [about 1920?] "The Lone Idealist" [1921?] "The Pulitzer Prize Piffle" [1926?] "For Mr. Stuart Chase, Technocrats, and Others" [1933?] Unidentified fragment (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Clippings: Editorial, Saturday Evening Post editorial pages, March 17, 1906-Oct. 27, 1906 "Unromantic War," 1918 "The Last Paradox," 1919 "There Are No Perfect Plays" [1920's?] "Advising U.S. to Get Out of Haiti, Prof. Herrick Accuses Marines," 1927 "Why American Literature is Insignificant," 1928 "Human Nature Axiom Used to Advantage by Selfish Citizens, Novelist Says," 1930 "The Necessity of Anonymity," 1931 "Maine's Charm Unique" [1930's?] (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Clippings: Book Reviews, Winston Churchill, Coniston, 1906 "The Drift of the Current" [1928] "A Feline World," 1929 "Fiction and Ideas," 1929 "Hermaphrodites," 1929 "What is Dirt?" 1929 "What Is Happening to Our Fiction?" 1929 Mazo De La Roche, Portrait of a Dog, 1930 Ludwig Lewisohn, The Golden Vase [1931] Theodore Dreiser, Dawn, 1931 F. O. Mann, Albert Grope, 1931 "The Works of Mrs. Woolf," 1931 (Box 17, Folder 22)
- Series V: Teaching Notes
  - Notebooks (2), 1892, Eighteenth Century English Literature 1893, Advanced English Composition (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks (2), 1897 English 5 and English 1 1897 Seventeenth Century Prose (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Notebook (1), 1898 English 5 Published book: Special Edition, Exercises in Rhetoric and Composition by G. R. Carpenter (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - "Technique of Novel," 1908, typescript (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - "Contemporary Literature Summer 1917," holograph and typescript, course outline and notes (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks (2), 1919 Contemporary Literature 1920-1921 Contemporary Literature (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Series VI: World War I Papers, Articles and Memorabilia
  - Articles and typescripts by subject, The Front The Marne & Reims No title Atrocities Industrial and Social America and the War Plan of War Book (Cf. The World Decision, 1916.) General (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - "From Week to Week or Women, War and Books" [1915?] 44 Chicago Tribune articles, clippings, grouped by Herrick and projected as a book; letter from Brett at Macmillan Company (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Chicago Tribune Articles: Women, "What Women Say about Themselves-One" "What Women Say about Themselves-The New Home" "What Women Say about Themselves-Women; Not Woman!" "What Women Say about Themselves-Mother-liness" "What Women Say about Themselves-The Race" "What Men Say about Women" "The Woman Question-Conclusions" "The Woman Question-Conclusions Two" "Women Again-Free Love" "A Woman's Business" "Three American Women" "Mrs. Norris" (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Chicago Tribune Articles: Books and Journalism, typescripts, "What the Public Wants" "Finding a Way" No title: [Devices Publishers Use to Arouse Interest in a Book] "Taboo" "Shakespeare as Neurasthenic" No title: [The New Poetry] "Doped Literature," 2 versions "Chronic Optimism" "How One Does It" "Definitions" "The Burden of the Past" "Good Journalism" "Polite Piffle" "A Favorite Vice," and fragments No title: [Of Henry Sydnor Harrison] Fragments (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Chicago Tribune Articles: Theatre, Social Life and Customs, typescripts, "Twaddle about the Theatre" (typescript and galley) "Anarchy" "Publicity" "A Sea Chance" "What is Decent?" March 12, 1916 "Talk" "Autumn Fires" "Alarms" "Gossip" "A New Departure" "Society" "How Democracy Takes Bad Luck" No title: [The Salem Fire] "The New Salem" "The Collector" "Diplomacy" "Portraits: The Profession of Diplomacy" "Portraits: Reactionaries, How to Settle a Strike" "Money Mysteries," Feb. 6, 1916 "Home Building" "The Crime of Being Rich and Other Things" "Getting Votes" "Bosh" "Who Pays?" (holograph) (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Chicago Tribune Articles: War, typescripts, early versions, "Rome," April 29, 1915 (holograph, 1 leaf) "Traveling in War Time" "What Makes the Happiness of a Country," 2 versions "The Childishness of Man" "Italia Comediante," 2 versions No title, begins: "Just at dawn this morning..." "The Attack on Venice" "Why Italy Went into the War," May 23, 1915, 2 versions "The New ltaly, "original and copy "The Case of Italy" "The First of May" No title, begins: "On the steamer last week..." "The Vote" (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Notes and Essays, Clipping "Conclusions," holograph "The Crucial Test," holograph (See "Conclusions," above.) "The World Mind" [1915?] "The Wounded" List of articles, holograph [1916?] "Style" [1916?] "The Margin of Civilization" "Playing Safe" "The Moral Stain," fragment Fragments, unidentified (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - "Portraits-D" [early?] typescript (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - "The Pacifist Warrior," Sept. 18-19, 1916, typescript, published as "A Soldier Pacifist," Scribner's, 62 (Aug. 1917), 247-250 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Chicago Tribune Articles, New Series 1916, typescripts, List of titles, 1 p. "Italia Vindicata," Jan. 16, 1916 "The Way of Germany and the Way of Russia" "What Would Happen if Germany Got Us" "What's in a Name?" "Can Democracy Save Itself?" March 19, 1916 "Verdun Again," March 5, 1916 "Premature Peace" "A Deadlier War," 2 versions "The Kaiser's Friends" "The New World" "An Example and a Warning" (about Ordeal by Battle) "Wanted-Men" (about Ordeal by Battle) "That Old German God," April 2, 1916 "The Tribal Man" "Perfidious Albion" "Human Nature Again!" "The Officer Class" "The War at Home" "The Wall" "The Great Delusion" "The Soldier's Honor" "Working for Peace" "The Administration" "Being Governed" "The Little Cogs in the Government Machine" (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - "The Chivalrous Heart," typescript, published as "Introduction," Poemes des Poilus, Boston: W. A. Butterfield, 1917 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - "Two Kinds of Philanthropy" [1917?] typescript (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Tribune Articles, 1917, typescripts, "Wheat and Chaff," March 14, 1917 "The Dawn," March 16, 1917 "A War Museum," March 20, 1917 "Peace Without Victory-a Draw," March 21, 1917 "It is War!" March 24, 1917 "Two Bad Books," March 25, 1917 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Rejected Chicago Tribune Articles-Plaintiff's Exhibit No. 235 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Essays [after his return to U.S.] typescripts, "The Bloody Mouthed" "Memorial Day, 1919" "Telling the Truth about War," 2 versions, Nation, 110 (June 26, 1920), 850a-851a "The Next War" (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - "The Open Mind" [after Armistice] typescript, text and fragment (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - "Our War and After" [after Armistice] typescript (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - "A Covenant, Not a Contract," April 2, 1919 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - "Fontenoy," typescript, notes and text, unpublished war book (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - "The Departure," typescript, a version of "Fontenoy" (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - "A French Point of View," typescript, related to "Fontenoy" (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - "The Quiet Sector," typescript, related to "Fontenoy" (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - "Tomorrow," holograph, 2 notebooks, war book (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - "Tomorrow," holograph and typescript, notes and text (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - French MS: "Souvenir de Captivité de 5 Mois passer en Allemagne," by Rene Favre, holograph (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - French Soldier's MS, typescript (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - French Soldier's MS (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - French Soldier's MS (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - French Magazines, 1915 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - 1915-1917, French driver's license, with his picture attached Permis de séjour, with his picture attached French clippings Pictures of 2 women Address book Notebook with notes for Tribune articles Cards and addresses of friends Hotel bills Large poster (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - 1915-1917, French clippings Report and part of a letter concerning Assoc. de L'Aisne dévastée Photographs and post cards depicting effects of war, especially Dans L'Aisne (See also "Fontenoy," above.) Papers relating to Association de L'Aisne dévastée and FontenoyArmy order by General Roques Magazine clippings (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - 1915-1917, Passports Permission slips, one with his picture attached (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - 1919-1917: Clippings (Note: "Robert Herrick Tells How War Is Made.") (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Series VII: Virgin Islands Papers
  - Documents, Letter from Paul M. Pearson, Governor, to Harmon Lewis Bill of Lading, Feb. 14, 1935 Examination of Schools, May 6, 1935 Minutes of a meeting of the Labor Board, May 14, 1935 Press Release, May 27, 1935, 2 copies Labor Board Release Executive Pardon for George S. Robinson, Government Attorney, June 18, 1935 Fourth of July Program Press Release, July 24, 1935 Radio Diffusion du Janvier 1936 Campagnie Générale Transatlantique, December 10, 1935, Liste des Passagers Warning Sign Tropical diseases, 1 p. "From Gettysburg Oration," also "Declaration of Independence," 2 pp. "Homesteading in the Virgin Islands 1931 to 1935" by Harry E. Taylor, Commissioner of Industry, Chairman, Homestead Commissions, 10 leaves "Truth about the Virgins," Herrick's notes for a book, typescript, 1 p. "Program for Virgin Islands," Herrick's typescript, 3 pp. Two picture postcards of Labor meetings (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Writings, "The Diary of a Government Secretary," typescript and holograph, 25 leaves "The Romance of the Caribbean," typescript notes, 2 leaves (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Clippings: U.S. and Virgin Islands newspapers (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Series VIII: Reviews of the Novels
  - 1894-1897 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - 1900 The Web of Life (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - 1900 The Web of Life (Box 22, Folder 1-4)
  - 1902 The Real World (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - 1903 Their Child (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - 1904 The Common Lot (Box 22, Folder 7-9)
  - 1905 Memoirs of an American Citizen (Box 22, Folder 10-11)
  - 1908 Master of the Inn (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - 1908 Together (Box 22, Folder 13-15)
  - 1908 Together (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - 1912 The Healer (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - 1913 His Great Adventure (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - 1913 One Woman's Life (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - 1914 Clark's Field (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - 1916-1918 World Decision, Conscript Mother, Poèmes des Poilus (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - 1923 Homely Lilla and Henry James essay (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - 1924 Waste (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - 1925 Wanderings (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - 1926 Chimes (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - 1932 The End of Desire (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Series IX: Oversize
  - The Man Who Wins, manuscript, 1897 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - The Gospel of Freedom, 1898, holograph, Part III (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - The Web of Life, 1900, holograph (Box 24, Folder 3-6)
  - Their Child, 1903, holograph (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - "The Polity of Nature," 1900, holograph, published Lippincott's, 68 (Oct. 1901), 458-471 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - "Mother Bates," 1900, holograph and printed version, published as "Mother Sims," Saturday Evening Post, 173 (Nov. 17, 1900) (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - "Elise," July 1, 1900, typescript (Cf. The Real World.) (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - "The End of Desire," 1902, holograph, published Atlantic Monthly, 92 (Oct. 1903), 462-69 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - "Common Honesty," 1900, holograph, published Saturday Evening Post, 176 (Sept. 19, 1903), 2-5, 28-30 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Novels [n.d.] holograph (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Portrait by Laurence Donovan - Artist’s Proof. 1974 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Fourteen issues of Saturday Evening Post April 1, 1905-July 1, 1905 (contains “Memoirs of an American Citizen”) (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1914 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, January - July 1915 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, August - December 1915 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1916 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1917 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Newspapers, 1915-1917 (Box 26)
- Series X: Miscellaneous Correspondence, Interviews and Ephemera
  Series X consists of addenda materials including letters written to Blake Nevius in response to his inquiries concerning the life and work of the American novelist, Robert Herrick [1868-1938], as well as other research materials. One or two of the letters were written when Nevius was preparing his Ph.D. dissertation at the University of Chicago on "The Novels of Robert Herrick" in 1946-7; most of the letters, however, are dated ca. 1951-1960 when he was working on the biographical study, Robert Herrick: The Development of a Novelist (University of California Press, 1962). The collection includes correspondence with friends, students, and colleagues of Herrick, among whom are the novelist Winston Churchill, Robert Morss Lovett, John P. Marquand, Forrest Rosaire, Edward Wagenknecht; Herrick's housekeeper during his last years, Miss Annie Luckie; Philip Herrick, the author's son; librarians and custodians of Herrick manuscripts, and researchers working for Nevius. Photocopies of letters from George Santayana and Bernard Berenson to Mrs. Barnet Levy are also included. One folder contains transcripts of interviews with Philip Herrick; another, miscellaneous materials related to Robert Herrick: copies of several of his letters; a map of Cambridge, Massachusetts as it was during Herrick's youth, and miscellaneous research notes.
  - Correspondence, Arvin, Newton-Churchill, Winston (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Dodge, Esther S.-Dorman, Estelle H. (Box 27, Folder 2)